Mukesh Manral

Data Scientist - CloudyML

■ mukeshmanral777@gmail.com \$\mathbb{k}\$ 8384801974 \$\mathbb{Q}\$ Gurugram, Haryana in Linkeln \$\mathbb{G}\$ Github

Profile

1+ years of experience in data science and analytics. Worked with service-based startup as well as product-based startup and played a big role in scaleup of data science and analytics team along with the business.

Technical Skills

- Python Machine Learning Deep Learning Computer Vision NLP AWS
- Streamlit Pandas Numpy scikit-learn tensor-flow keras opencv

Professional Experience

Data Scientist, CloudyML ∅

June 2021 - present

- Communicated effectively with team and external stakeholders.
- Created roadmaps for various data science courses and helped in launching.
- Facilitated data cleansing, enrichment and data quality improvements.
- Analysed and organized raw data.
- Helped other stakeholders like the Marketing and Growth product team to hire the right Analyst based on various use cases.
- Have delivered complete product marketing reports to CEO and CMO in a very short span of time which was urgent and used efficiently in creating annual operation plans for various segments.

Machine Learning Engineer, TechSim+

January 2020 -December 2020

Client : One Financial Corporation Project-1 : Loan Underwriting

- Preprocessed entire dataset and Selected most important 30 features
- Boosted model efficiency by almost 5%.
- Validated model efficiency using matrix like classification Reports, confusion matrix, AUC Sscore.

Project-2: Customer Churn Prediction

- Preprocessed data and Performed Feature selection.
- Decreased churn rate by 2%
- Purposed different marking scheams as to retain churning customer

Certification

Master Data Science for Industry-(Ascend Pro), Link: ⊘

November 2020 – October 2021

- Attended 12 Months Training on Full Stack Data Science for Industry

- Institute : Analytics Vidhya & KPMG India Got exposure to following areas of Data Science :
 - Tools like Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scikitlearn, Keras, OpenCv, Tableau, MongoDB, SQL, Spacy, Spark, AWS.
 - Industry like Consumer Market & Telecom, Financial Services, Life Science and Farma.

Machine Learning by Stanford University (Coursera),

May 2020 - July 2020

Link: ⊘

Achievements

Machine Hack Data Hackon, Link: ∂

Global Ranking of 315

Kaggle, Link: ∂

Pain Point: Like others I have to invested a ton of time and money in exploring Machine Learning and Deep Learning

AIM: To make easy to follow Machine Learning and Deep Learning framework in simple words Written easy to follow kernels on different Machine Learning Algorithms and Deep Learning

Github, Link: ∂

Sharing my knowledge with Data Science community

Education

Bachelor's in Computer Science Engineering, Uttarakhand Technical University June 2015 - July 2019